https://www.linkedin.com/in/fouche-van-den-berg-02a5a3170/

Personal:

Email: fouchevandenberg@gmail.com

Date Of Birth: 12th of June 2000

Nationality: South African

Cell: 064 793 9119

Address:

206 Big Bay Beach Club

Big Bay, Table View Cape Town

7441

Profile:

Highly self-motivated ambitious young man that has constructed short and long term goals, to achieve these goals, self- discipline was required to execute these plans. The 3 years in the work force established a better understanding of the business world and elicited a third quality that is required in achieving goals, Perseverance. The passion for computers and technology originated as a child and the power of programming was applied to almost every aspect of previous positions, in the past 3 years, to efficiently execute the job accurately and methodically. The power of computers and the thrill of the business world has cemented a new passion of mine which is bringing business and technology together.

Education:

Fairmont High School:

Matriculated | 2018

The subjects that I matriculated in were as follows:

- Mathematics
- Physical Sciences
- Business studies
- Information Technology
- English Home Language
- Afrikaans First Additional Language Distinction
- Life Orientation Distinction

UNISA:

First Year Student | 2022

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Applied Mathematics

Currently enrolled at UNISA with the following modules:

- APM1513: Applied Linear AlgebraCOS1501: Theoretical Computing
- COS1511: Intro to Programming ICOS1512: Intro to Programming II
- COS1521: Computer Systems: Fundamental Concepts
- MAT1503: Linear Algebra
- MAT1512: Calculus A
- MAT1613: Calculus B

Certificates:

Modena Training:

Revit advanced course | 2020

Certified in the advanced capabilities of the Revit Autodesk Software:

- Capable of creating and effectively using schedules
- Create accurate families with the correct elements
- Able to do an accurate HVAC and plumbing design from scratch

EMCARE training academy:

First Aid Level I | 2019

Certified in all the basic skills of First Aid and certification expires on the 5th of July 2022 of which I was educated in:

- Principles of Emergency Care & Safety
- Shock, Unconscious & Fainting
- Emergency Scene Management
- Fractures
- Artificial Respiration
- Burns
- One Rescuer Adult CPR
- Head & Spinal Injuries
- Choking
- Emergency Care Equipment
- Wounds & Bleeding
- Legal & Ethical implications related to emergency care

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fouche-van-den-berg-02a5a3170/

Protrack Anti-Poaching Unit:

PSIRA Registered | 2019

Certified, assessed and found competent in the PSIRA Grade Training course:

Grade E Certified

- PSIRA Reg: 0351350/T413

Firearms Training | 2019

Tested in the theoretical and the practical aspects of firearm training and declared proficient in:

- Knowledge of the Firearms Control Act 2000 (Act no 60 of 2000) (117705)
- Handle and use of a Self-Loading Rifle or Carbine (119650)
- Handle and use of a Self-Loading Rifle or Carbine in business use (123511)

Van Zyl & Pritchard's:

Wrote a competency test which evaluates logic, concentration and understanding of programming concepts.

- Concentration 1 100%
- Perception 2 100%
- Spec Reading 3 75%
- Concept of Tables 4 20%
- Concept of Pointers 5 100%
- OVERALL: 79%

Skills:

Technical Skills:

Proficient with the following software and programming languages:

- Delphi Programming Language
- Iron python
- Dynamo (BIM)
- Autodesk Revit
- Autodesk AutoCAD
- Microsoft Office Applications

Intermediate level with the following software and programming languages:

- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

Beginner level with the following software and programming languages:

- C# and C++

Social Skills:

Good understanding of business concepts and the ability to sell a product or a brand:

- Capable of growing a company brand
- Efficient at growing and managing a client portfolio
- Able to forge new customer leads and manage existing leads
- Construct an effective pipeline of opportunities
- Deliver effective customer service to all clients
- Authored effective sales proposals and present confidently to clients
- Proficient capability of analysing the market and providing new and creative solutions.

Mechanical Skills:

A good understanding of mechanical concepts and the way things work on a mechanical level:

- Proficient understanding of HVAC drawings and the way air conditioning systems operate
- Proficient understanding of drainage drawings and the way drainage systems work
- Proficient understanding of domestic Water drawings and the way domestic water systems operate
- Proficient understanding of fire Drawings and the level of details required to create an effective fire drawing

Practical Skills:

Skills that can be applied in the field or have a physical element to it:

- Basic understanding of how to work with aerial support
- Effective Tracking capabilities in the bushveldt
- Good communication skills in terms of operating a radio
- Capable to identify gunshot distance, degrees, direction, and calibre type
- Capable in self defence and able to teach and educate others in Boxing.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fouche-van-den-berg-02a5a3170/

Work Experience:

Community Service:

Any activity that I have done to assist the community around me or communities near me

- Volunteer work in Zimbabwe during School Holidays
- Did community Service assisting at the Animal Anti-Cruelty League

2019:

This time was used to educate myself in other avenues before pursuing my career goals:

 Trained as a ranger at Protrack Anti-Poaching Unit

2019 - 2021:

After multiple injuries during 2019, entering the work force to get valuable experience was the next step:

- Worked at Dihlase Consulting Engineers as a BIM Technician from October 2019 -March 2021
- Worked part time at Harringtons cocktail lounge as a Cocktail bartender from November 2019 – November 2020
- Worked at Airco (Pty LTD) as an External Sales Consultant from April 2021 – December 2021.

2022:

Started following the steps of entering the industry that I am passionate about and studying.

- Freelance Web Developer from January 2022
- Started my studies as a Student in BSc Computer Science and applied mathematics at UNISA
- Still Continuing with my journey as an Amateur Boxer.

Projects:

Software Development Projects:

Projects | Front End Developer

Cellador Website

 (WIP) Currently in the process of creating an interactive website for a Wine Merchant located in the Cape using HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Projects | BIM Technician

Automatic Sprinkler Placement Script

 (Internal Project) A Node/Code Script being created to automate Sprinkler Placements accurately throughout a drawing following ASIB Standards using Dynamo BIM and Iron Python

Automatic Pipe Sizing for Wet Services

 A Node/Code Script being created to accurately calculate pipe sizes throughout a drawing following ASIB Standards for Fire Protection and SANS for Wet Services using Dynamo BIM and Iron Python Scripts

Mechanical Projects:

New Era Health | BIM Technician

- Assisted with Fire engineer with drawings and designs for the project
- Assisted mechanical team and engineers with drawings and designs for the project

ACSA Domestic Departures | BIM Technician

 Assisted mechanical engineering team with the drawings and designs

Sonstraal Hospital | BIM Technician

 Assisted the lead mechanical engineer with the drawings and designs.

Valkenberg Hospital | BIM Technician

- Assisted the mechanical engineering team with drawings and designs

GDID Jubilee | BIM Technician

Assisted the mechanical engineer with drawings and designs

Belvedere | BIM Technician

 Assisted the Fire Engineer with fire drawings and designs

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fouche-van-den-berg-02a5a3170/

Sports and Hobbies:

Sports Experience:

Boxing | Amateur Level

- Started my boxing career in June 2021
- Ended 2021 with 3 wins and 0 Losses
- Still currently an amateur boxer

Swimming | National Level

- Went to National Level 2 for swimming
- 13th in South Africa in 2011 for u/11 50m Freestyle
- SWD Colours for Swimming
- Received multiple scholarships from Swimming clubs for swimming

U19 | High School Level

- High School 1st team Water Polo and Captain
- High School 1st Team Swimming
- High School 1st Team Rugby

Hobbies:

Hobbies and Activities that I am passionate about

- Motocross
- Car Collections
- Computers and Video games
- Combat Sports
- Nature Conservation
- Sports
- Chess

References and Testimonials:

High School Testimonial:

Ms T.Moore: "Fouche is friendly, outgoing young man with a lovely sense of humour. He is reliable and hardworking, he has approached all his duties with energy and completes all tasks given to him. He has been a committed swimmer and water polo player, never letting the team down and working hard to reach the goals he has set himself. His self-discipline is to be commended. Fouche has always shown respect to younger learners, his peers and those in authority. His sense of pride, in everything he did was evident. He has a, he is a cheerful disposition, and is a lively young man who approaches life with vigour.

We wish him well in his future endeavours."

DATE ISSUED: 26 November 2018

References:

Ossie Lamb (Former employer): 082 838 8821 Wynand Venter (Mechanical Engineer): 082 746 0979

Jano Bekker (BIM Manager): 084 627 9709